Guide to the Frances Hesselbein Papers, 1942-2013 AIS.2013.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Frances Hesselbein Personal Papers, ca. 1930s-1940s, 1955-2014; B.
  - Speeches, 1976-2013; VII.
    - Hesselbein speeches, 1976-1987; 1.
      - Speeches, 2004
        - "Challenge of Leading Change" - Geneva College Roundtable Questions, April 7, 2004; 6.
        - "Journey to Transformation" - Penn State, April 14, 2004; 7.
        - Junior Achievement Award Dinner speech, July 8, 2004; 8.
        - Executive Women International Leadership Summit Luncheon speech, July 9, 2004; 9.
        - Columbia University speech, July 13, 2004; 10.
        - New York City Principals speech, July 29, 2004; 11.
        - "Leadership Imperatives in an Age of Change and Discontinuity" - New Zealand Institute of Management, October 8, 2004; 1. (Box 29, Folder 8)
        - Speech to Wellington Rotary Club, October 11, 2004; 2.
        - "Leadership Imperatives: The Future of Business" - Crew Network, October 15, 2004; 3.
      - Speeches, 2005
        - "Leadership Imperatives for the 21st Century" - Maxwell Air Force Base, May 25, 2005; 1. (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Speeches, 2006
        - Minnesota Health and Housing Alliance 2006 Symposium and Expo speech, February 1, 2006; 1. (Box 29, Folder 10)
        - "One Movement...One Conversation" - Girl Scouts of the USA Board Chairs and CEOs Work Session, February 2006; 2.
      - Speeches, 2007
        - "Imperatives of Leadership" - Telecom Pioneers, February 17, 2007; 1. (Box 29, Folder 11)
        - "A Girl's World is Different", February 22, 2007; 2.
        - Taiwan leadership speech, March 15, 2007; 3.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Hope of the Future" - Juniata College, April 4, 2007; 4.
        - "Leaders of the Future - Hope of the Future" - Penn Consortium, April 4, 2007; 5.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Hope of the Future" - St. John's Northwestern Military Academy, April 29, 2007; 6.
        - "The Leader of the Future: The New Leadership" - Fidelity Investments, May 1, 2007; 7.
        - The Drucker Society Global Symposium speech, June 25, 2007; 8.
        - "Touching the Hearts of Children" - Military Child Education Coalition Annual Conference, July 11, 2007; 9.
        - Junior Achievement International speech, July 12, 2007; 10.
        - Generals in Transition dinner, August 14, 2007; 11.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Imperatives of Leadership" - Caregivers, September 5, 2007; 12.
        - Frances Hesselbein's citation of Andrea Jung, October 9, 2007; 13.
        - "Leader of the Future" - Under Armour, October 11, 2007; 14.
        - Diversity Breakfast at the Pentagon speech, November 29, 2007; 15.
        - Center for Public Leadership - John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University speech, December 11, 2007; 16.
      - Speeches, 2008
        - "Collaborative Leadership" - The American Institute of Architects Grassroots Leadership and Legislative Conference, February 22, 2008; 1. (Box 29, Folder 12)
        - Rainbow Days National Partnership Award speech, February 28, 2008; 2.
        - Speech to Girl Scouts of Western Pennsylvania, March 8, 2008; 3.
        - "Imperatives of Leadership: The University of the Future" - Global Perspectives in a Southern African Context, April 24, 2008; 4.
        - Women's Leadership Summit - United Way of Baltimore, May 13, 2008; 5.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Imperatives of Leadership" - Seattle Library Association, June 16, 2008; 6.
        - Giftleaders conference speech, July 11, 2008; 7.
        - "The Practice of Management: The World Peter Drucker Created", September 17, 2008; 8.
        - New York City Leadership Center Launch dinner speech, September 18, 2008; 9.
        - Daytime event - New York City Leadership Center, September 18, 2008; 10.
        - New York City Leadership Center speech, September 20, 2008; 11.
        - Chevron Management Institute speech, September 26, 2008; 12.
      - Speeches, 2009
        - Babson College - Issues in Leadership and Ethics Course presentation, February 19, 2009; 1. (Box 29, Folder 13)
        - Girl Scout Leadership Conference speech, February 27, 2009; 2.
        - Chevron Management Institute speech, October 9, 2009; 3.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Imperatives of Leadership", October 2009; 4.
        - "Leadership Lessons and Imperatives", December 2, 2009; 5.
      - Speeches, 2010
        - "Leadership Lessons and Imperatives" - U.S. Air Force Academy, February 17, 2010; 1. (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Speeches, 2011
        - "A Challenge to Serve is to Live" - Women's Network for a Sustainable Future, January 18, 2011; 1. (Box 29, Folder 15)
        - "Leaders of the Future: Challenges and Opportunities" - Guardian Life Leadership Conference, March 17, 2011; 2.
        - Farewell speech to the Class of 1951 Leadership Chair, April 28, 2011; 3.
        - Athena Award speech, May 2, 2011; 4.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Imperatives of Leadership", June 9, 2011; 1. (Box 29, Folder 16)
        - Speech to AARP, June 12, 2011; 2.
        - "A Call to Service and Leadership" - National Summit of Vietnamese American Leaders, July 2, 2011; 3.
        - Hesselbein Global Academy Honoring Students Ceremony speech, July 2011; 4.
        - "Leadership Lessons and Imperatives" - Hesselbein Global Academy closing speech, July 2011; 5.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Challenges and Opportunities" - Bennett College, August 11, 2011; 6.
        - Generals in Transition dinner speech, October 19, 2011; 1. (Box 29, Folder 17)
        - "Leader of the Future", November 1, 2011; 2.
        - "Peter Drucker's Five Questions Self-Assessment Tool" - New York City Leadership Center, November 30, 2011; 3.
      - Speeches, 2012
        - "Leaders of the Future: Challenges and Opportunities" - Babson College, March 8, 2012; 1. (Box 29, Folder 18)
        - Speech to the Girl Scouts of the USA, March 27, 2012; 2.
        - "The Leaders of the Future: Challenges and Opportunities" - Arizona Girl Scouts Luncheon speech, April 2012; 3.
        - Girl Scouts Keynote speech - Girl Scouts of Arizona Cactus-Pine, April 28, 2012; 4.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Challenges and Opportunities" - West Chester University, May 14, 2012; 5.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Imperatives of Leadership" - Philanthropy Workshop, May 14, 2012; 6.
        - TEDx MidAtlantic Conference presentation, October 27, 2012; 7.
        - "Leaders of the Future: Imperatives of Leadership" - Forest Laboratories, December 18, 2012; 1. (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - Speeches, 2013
        - Frances Hesselbein/Marshall Goldsmith West Point webinar, January 15, 2013; 1. (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - Speeches and excerpts, undated
        - "Monday Night Toast to Peter Drucker", undated; 1. (Box 29, Folder 21)
        - "Kellogg" speech excerpt, undated; 2.
        - "Lake Geneva" speech excerpt, undated; 3.
        - "United Way - SAC" excerpt, undated; 4.
        - "Lutheran" speech excerpt, undated; 5.
        - "The Defining Moment" speech excerpt, undated; 6.
        - "Servant-Leadership and the Organization of the Future" speech, undated; 7.
        - "How Can We Lose When We Are So Sincere?" speech excerpt, undated; 8.
        - Four untitled speech excerpts, undated; 9.
        - World Economic Forum remarks - excerpts, undated; 1. (Box 29, Folder 22)
        - American Institute of Architects excerpts, undated; 2.
        - "Leadership in a World of Change" excerpts, undated; 3.
        - "Dinner remarks", undated; 4.
        - Houston SAT II speech, undated; 5.
        - Three untitled speech excerpts, undated; 6.
        - "London" speech excerpt, undated; 1. (Box 29, Folder 23)
        - "The Power Within", undated; 2.
        - "Sonoma" speech excerpt, undated; 3.
        - International Leadership Association of Toronto, Canada, undated; 4.
        - "The Challenge of Leadership Transition: The Ultimate Management Challenge", undated; 5.
        - "Notre Dame" speech excerpt, undated; 6.
        - "A Challenge to Governance and Management", undated; 7.
        - "FWI" speech excerpt, undated; 8.
        - Eight untitled speech excerpts, undated; 9.
        - "Voluntarism" - New Zealand, undated; 1. (Box 29, Folder 24)
        - Drucker Innovation Award speech - Korea, undated; 2.
        - "The Power Within", undated; 3.
        - "The Art of Listening", undated; 4.
        - "From Good to Great", undated; 5.
        - "Globalization" - Jane Addams Hull House, undated; 6.
        - "University of Vienna" excerpt, undated; 7.
        - "Arizona State University" excerpt, undated; 8.
        - Lafayette College citation, undated; 9.
        - "Communication - Power of Language", undated; 10.
        - "Drucker Foundation Revisits" excerpt, undated; 11.
        - Recycled speech excerpts, 1990s-2000s (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - American Association of Homes for the Aging speeches, 1990s (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - American Cancer Society speech notes, September 1995 (Box 29, Folder 27)
      - Australian Forum for Nonprofit Leadership speeches, April 1999 (Box 29, Folder 28)
      - Barriers to Leadership speeches and notes, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Boston College Commencement Award dinner speech materials, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - BusinessWeek Symposium speech notes, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - "Challenge the Gospel" speech and notes, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - "Change Process" - SRC Monitoring Group speech notes, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Council on Foundations speech and materials, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Davos World Economic Forum Denmark speeches, April 2000 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Davos World Economic Forum speeches and notes, 2000s (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - "Definition of Leadership" speech notes, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Doug McMullen retirement speech and materials, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - "East-West" speech notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
      - Fairfield University Olin Lecture, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 12)
      - Fordham University Dinner speech and materials, 1998-1999 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - Harvard University speech and notes, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Hershey speech and notes, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - "Journey to Leadership" speech/presentation plans, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - Juniata College Commencement speech and materials, May 13, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - Kellogg speech notes, April 1994 (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - Leader to Leader speech drafts and notes, March 2000 (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - "Leading the Transformation" presentation, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 20)
      - Luzerne County Commission for Women speech notes, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - Managing for the Mission speech and notes, November 1985 (Box 30, Folder 22)
      - Marshall Goldsmith video speeches, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 23)
      - Melbourne Citymission speeches and event materials, April 2004 (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - Melbourne Citymission speech notes and excerpts, April 2004 (Box 30, Folder 25-26)
      - "Save the Children" speech drafts, undated (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - Singapore Youth Council speeches and materials, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 28)
      - SUNY New Paltz Foundation speeches and notes, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 29)
      - Talus Rock Girl Scout Council speech and materials, April 1992 (Box 30, Folder 30)
      - Texaco Management Institute speech #1, May 1999 (Box 30, Folder 31)
      - Texaco Management Institute speech #2, May 1999 (Box 30, Folder 32)
      - Texaco Management Institute speech #3, May 1999 (Box 30, Folder 33)
      - Texaco Management Institute speech #4, May 1999 (Box 30, Folder 34)
      - Texaco Management Institute speech #7, May 1999 (Box 30, Folder 35)
      - Texaco Management Institute speech #8, May 1999 (Box 30, Folder 36)
      - West Point Military Child Education Coalition speech and materials, September 2011 (Box 30, Folder 37)
      - "What Businesses Can Learn From One Another" - World President's Organization Dallas Chapter, April 9, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 38)
      - "When They Look at Us..." presentation, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Yale School of Organization and Management speech and materials, May 1992 (Box 30, Folder 40)
      - Hesselbein handwritten speech notes and drafts, 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 41-42)
    - Speeches about Frances Hesselbein, 1998-2002, 2011-2013; 2. (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - President Clinton speech at Medal of Freedom ceremony, January 15, 1998; 1. (Box 30, Folder 43)
      - "A Personalized Paraphrase of the Prayer in John 17 for Frances Hesselbein", September 1999; 2.
      - Suzanne Carlton's speech at the Dwight D. Eisenhower National Security Award presentation, November 18, 2003; 3.
      - Thomas Moran's Presentation to Frances - Upon Completion of Her 2 Year Tenure as the Class of 1951 Leadership Chair, April 28, 2011; 4.
      - Charles J. O'Connor at the 50th Anniversary of the Presidential Medal of Freedom reception, November 20, 2013; 5.
    - Speech subject and reference files, 3. (Box 31, Folder 1-23, Box 30, Folder 44-102)
      - Speech subject files - "Accountability", 1993-1995 (Box 30, Folder 44)
      - Speech subject files - "Answer to Critics", April 1994 (Box 30, Folder 45)
      - Speech subject files - "Warren Bennis", 1988-1992, undated (Box 30, Folder 46)
      - Speech subject files - "Boundaryless Company", 1992 (Box 30, Folder 47)
      - Speech subject files - "George H.W. Bush", June 1989 (Box 30, Folder 48)
      - Speech subject files - "Business and Government", June 1993 (Box 30, Folder 49)
      - Speech subject files - "CEO's Reading List", July 1991 (Box 30, Folder 50)
      - Speech subject files - "Center for Public Leadership", 2011-2012 (Box 30, Folder 51)
      - Speech subject files - "Children in Crisis", August 10, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 52)
      - Speech subject files - "Church Groups", 1991-1992 (Box 30, Folder 53)
      - Speech subject files - "Circular management", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 54)
      - Speech subject files - "Clinton/nonprofit sector", May 4, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 55)
      - Speech subject files - "William Cohen", July 1998 (Box 30, Folder 56)
      - Speech subject files - "Robert Coles", November 15, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 57)
      - Speech subject files - "Corporate change", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 58)
      - Speech subject files - "Corporate community service", 1993 (Box 30, Folder 59)
      - Speech subject files - "Crisis management", June 28, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 60)
      - Speech subject files - "Crisis of credibility", June 14, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 61)
      - Speech subject files - "Customer service", 1991 (Box 30, Folder 62)
      - Speech subject files - "Education", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 63)
      - Speech subject files - "Effective Executive", 1989, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 64)
      - Speech subject files - "Ethics", 1992-1993 (Box 30, Folder 65)
      - Speech subject files - "Executive Book Summaries", March 1996 (Box 30, Folder 66)
      - Speech subject files - "Family and Work", June 28, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 67)
      - Speech subject files - "Female style management", 1990 (Box 30, Folder 68)
      - Speech subject files - "Fund Development", 1992 (Box 30, Folder 69)
      - Speech subject files - "John Gardner", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 70)
      - Speech subject files - "General Electric", August 1996 (Box 30, Folder 71)
      - Speech subject files - "Global economy", February 1, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 72)
      - Speech subject files - "Peter Goldmark", October 15, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 73)
      - Speech subject files - "Governance", 1995 (Box 30, Folder 74)
      - Speech subject files - "Harvard Business School", 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 75)
      - Speech subject files - "Regina Herzlinger", January 1995 (Box 30, Folder 76)
      - Speech subject files - "Hire Smart", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 77)
      - Speech subject files - "International Philanthropy", 1992 (Box 30, Folder 78)
      - Speech subject files - "Innovation", undated (Box 30, Folder 79)
      - Speech subject files - "Michael Josephson", May 22, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 80)
      - Speech subject files - "Journey to Leadership", 1999 (Box 30, Folder 81)
      - Speech subject files - "Lamentations", 1997 (Box 30, Folder 82)
      - Speech subject files - "Leader list", June 1994 (Box 30, Folder 83)
      - Speech subject files - "Leader to Leader journal", 1997 (Box 30, Folder 84)
      - Speech subject files - "Leadership", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 85)
      - Speech subject files - "Lufthansa", 1993 (Box 30, Folder 86)
      - Speech subject files - "Machiavelli", undated (Box 30, Folder 87)
      - Speech subject files - "Management", October 1994 (Box 30, Folder 88)
      - Speech subject files - "Management Gurus", 1989, 1990s (Box 30, Folder 89)
      - Speech subject files - "Marketing", undated (Box 30, Folder 90)
      - Speech subject files - "MBA", 1991-1993 (Box 30, Folder 91)
      - Speech subject files - "Mentors", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 92)
      - Speech subject files - "Military Confidence poll", 1990s-2000s (Box 30, Folder 93)
      - Speech subject files - "Mission", August 1992 (Box 30, Folder 94)
      - Speech subject files - "Monsanto", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 95)
      - Speech subject files - "New Wave management", 1990 (Box 30, Folder 96)
      - Speech subject files - "Nonprofit education", April 1991 (Box 30, Folder 97)
      - Speech subject files - "Nonprofit organizations", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 98)
      - Speech subject files - "Nonprofit tax exemptions", November 26, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 99)
      - Speech subject files - "New York Times articles", 1990s (Box 30, Folder 100)
      - Speech subject files - "Personal/Professional Renewal", 1992 (Box 30, Folder 101)
      - Speech subject files - "Philadelphia Inquirer", April 1993 (Box 30, Folder 102)
      - Speech subject files - "Philanthropy", 1990s (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Speech subject files - "Poverty", 1991 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Speech subject files - "Productivity", 1990s (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Speech subject files - "Race", 1999 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Speech subject files - "Reinventing America", 1992 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - Speech subject files - "Service Industry", April 21, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Speech subject files - "Speeches by others", 1990s-2000s (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - Speech subject files - "Strategic planning/mission", undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Speech subject files - "Arthur Taylor", October 25, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Speech subject files - "Teamwork", 1990s (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Speech subject files - "Technology", June 14, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Speech subject files - "Total Quality Management", 1991-1993 (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - Speech subject files - "Vision statement", June 1993 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      - Speech subject files - "Visionary leadership", 1992 (Box 31, Folder 14)
      - Speech subject files - "Volunteering", 1990s (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - Speech subject files - "Wall Street Journal article", October 10, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 16)
      - Speech subject files - "Jack Welch", undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
      - Speech subject files - "Wisdom of Teams", undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
      - Speech subject files - "Women's issues", 1990-1995 (Box 31, Folder 19)
      - Speech subject files - "Workplace education", February 1993 (Box 31, Folder 20)
      - Speech subject files - "Wall Street Journal - Executive Education", September 10, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 21)
      - Speech subject files - "Youth Service", July 27, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 22)
      - Speech subject files - "Zero Defects Management", 1990-1992 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Personal, 1963, 1993-2012; VIII.
    This series contains materials of a personal nature, such as pieces of writing from Frances Hesselbein's family members and birthday messages. It also includes a variety of certificates and awards given to Hesselbein over the course of her life. Media of a personal nature may be found in Series IX, which includes family photographs as well as videotapes of some of her public appearances. This series contains speech transcripts from Frances Hesselbein, speeches made about Frances Hesselbein, and reference material used to write speeches by Ms. Hesselbein. The speeches range in date from 1981 – 2013, though there are gaps in the time frame.
    - Awards, 1995-1996, 2003-2009 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Boston College honorary degree, May 23, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Family writings, 2011-2012, undated (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Hesselbein church presentation, March 6, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Family history, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Notes for Frances Hesselbein, 2010 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Birthday messages, undated (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Audio/Visual Material, 1930s-1940s, 1978-2013, undated; IX.
    This series contains the audio and video recordings in the Frances Hesselbein Personal Papers subgroup. Materials in this series include video cassettes, audio cassettes, CD-ROMs, DVDs, and photographic images. There are videos of Frances Hesselbein during her time with the Girl Scouts, as well as videos produced by that organization. The videos also include her personal appearances, such as the video broadcast of Hesselbein being awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom. The audio cassettes include dictated notes from Hesselbein, as well as some interviews. There are a select number of photographs, including some family photos dating throughout the 20th century.
    - Girl Scouts of the United States of America, 1978-1998, 2011; 1.
      - The 70th Anniversary Message from the National Executive Director, 1981 (Box 43, Video 1)
      - Peter Drucker Addresses the Executive Directors, September 1989 (Box 43, Video 2)
      - The 70th Anniversary Message from the National Executive Director, 1981 (Box 43, Video 3)
      - Girl Scouts - "On My Honor", undated (Box 43, Video 4)
      - National Meeting of Girl Scout Council Executive Directors, September 1989 (Box 43, Video 5)
      - Peter Drucker Presentation at the National Meeting of Girl Scout Council Executive Directors, September 1989 (Box 43, Video 6)
      - Dr. Warren Bennis Presentation at the National Meeting of Girl Scout Council Executive Directors, September 1989 (Box 43, Video 7)
      - Girl Scout National Council Session - 45th Convention, October 1990 (Box 43, Video 8)
      - National Meeting of Girl Scouts Council Executive Directors - Frances Hesselbein: "You're the Top", 1989 (Box 43, Video 9)
      - Corporate Planning in Girl Scouting: The People and the Process, October 25, 1988 (Box 43, Video 10)
      - Girl Scouts of America - Harvard Business School presentation, 1980s-1990s (Box 43, Video 11)
      - Girl Scouts - Eye to Eye report, January 27, 1994 (Box 43, Video 12)
      - History of Girl Scouts: Work-In-Progress ("Girl Scout 9 min clip"), undated (Box 43, Video 13)
      - CBS This Morning - "Girl Scout Birthday clip", March 12, 1991 (Box 43, Video 14)
      - Girl Scouts - Arizona Cactus Pine Council, undated (Box 43, Video 15)
      - Arizona Cactus-Pine Council - "Everything Flows from Mission", undated (Box 43, Video 16)
      - Badger Council video, 1990 (Box 43, Video 17)
      - "Women of Distinction" - Penn Laurel Girl Scout Council, May 21, 1996 (Box 43, Video 18)
      - Tejas Girl Scouts - Summer programs, 1990s (Box 43, Video 19)
      - National Meeting of Girl Scout Council Executive Directors - Peter Drucker presentation, September 1989 (Box 43, Cassette 1)
      - Peter F. Drucker Seminar for GSUSA - A Conversation with Peter Drucker and Frances Hesselbein, April 1989 (Box 43, Cassette 2)